import { useState } from "react"

function Quiz() {
    const questions = [
        {
          Question: "What is JSX?",
          option: [
            "JavaScript XML",
            "JawaScript XML",
            "JavaScript",
            "JS"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "JavaScript XML"
        }, 
        {
          Question: "What is CSS",
          option: [
            "Call Style Sheet",
            "Calling Styles Shirt",
            "Cascading Style Sheet",
            "CSS"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Cascading Style Sheet"
        },
        {
          Question: "What is JS?",
          option: [
            "JavaScript",
            "XML",
            "CSS",
            "JS"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "JavaScript"
        },
        {
          Question: "What is SQL?",
          option: [
            "Structure Querry Language",
            "Structure Quick Language",
            "SQL",
            "Strict Querry Lan"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Structure Querry Language"
        },
        {
          Question: "Which is an input device?",
          option: [
            "Mice",
            "Monitor",
            "Speaker",
            "Mouse"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Mouse"
        },
        {
          Question: "Which is output device?",
          option: [
            "Mouse",
            "Monitor",
            "Keyboard",
            "Trackpad"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Monitor"
        },
        {
          Question: "Which is the most powerful computer?",
          option: [
            "Mini computer",
            "Super computer",
            "Mainframe computer",
            "Wokstation computer"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Super computer"
        },
        {
          Question: "What is CISCO?",
          option: [
            "Programing Language",
            "Computer",
            "Networking software",
            "Hacking software"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Networking software"
        },
        {
          Question: "What is Linux?",
          option: [
            "Networking software",
            "Operating system",
            "Hacking software",
            "Operating software"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Operating system"
        },
        {
          Question: "What is PSU?",
          option: [
            "Power Supply Unit",
            "Power Suppliment Unit",
            "Power Suppliment UI",
            "Power Supply UI"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Power Supply Unit"
        },
        {
          Question: "What is GPU?",
          option: [
            "Grade Percentage Unit",
            "Video card",
            "Graphics Processing Unit",
            "CPU"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Graphics Processing Unit"
        },
        {
          Question: "How was this Quiz?",
          option: [
            "Easy",
            "Very Easy",
            "Very Very Easy",
            "Very Very Very Easy"
          ],
          correctAnswer: "Very Easy"
        }
      ]
    
      const [currentQuestionIndex, setcurrentQuestionIndex] = useState(0)
      const [score, setScore] = useState(0)
    
      const next = () => {
        //To cycle the questions
        setcurrentQuestionIndex(currentQuestionIndex + 1)
    
        //to cross check which radio button was selected and saving its value for right or wrong option
        const options = document.querySelectorAll('input[name="choice"]');
        let selectedValue;
        for (const option of options) {
             if (option.checked) {
                 selectedValue = option.value;
                 break;
                }
            }
        console.log(selectedValue);
    
        //to check if the selected option is correct or not
        {
          selectedValue == questions[currentQuestionIndex].correctAnswer &&
          setScore(score+1)
        }
      
      //for clearing the radio button for next question
      let radioBtn = document.getElementsByName("choice");
      for(var i=0; i<radioBtn.length; i++)
        radioBtn[i].checked = false;
      }
    
      const startAgain = () => {
        setcurrentQuestionIndex(0)
        setScore(0)
      }
    
      return (
        <div className="App">
          <header className="App-header">
            
              {
              //If
              currentQuestionIndex !== questions.length ?
                //fragment
                <>
                
                {/* <p>
                <Progress completed={(currentQuestionIndex+1)/questions.length} />
                </p> */}
    
                <p>
                  Question {currentQuestionIndex+1}/{questions.length}
                </p>
    
                  <h1>
                      Q. {questions[currentQuestionIndex].Question}
                  </h1>
    
                  <p>
                  {questions[currentQuestionIndex].option.map((item, index) => {
                          return <>
                          <input type="radio" name="choice" value={item} id={index}/>
                              {item}
                              <br></br>
                          </>
                      })}
                  </p>
    
                  <button onClick={next}>NEXT</button>
                </>
                //Else
                :
                <div>
                
                <h1>
                  QUIZ HAS ENDED
                </h1>
    
                <h2>
                  {console.log(score)}
                  {console.log(questions.length)}   
                  Score {score/(questions.length)*100}% 
                </h2>
                
                <p>
                  No. of correct answers {score}
                  {<br></br>}
                  No. of wrong answers {questions.length - score}
                </p>
    
                <button onClick={startAgain}>START AGAIN</button>
                
                </div>
              }
          </header>
        </div>
      );
    
}

export default Quiz
